This is software engineering radio, the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-radio.net.
SE Radio is brought to you by the ITE
computer society and by it e software
magazine online at
computer.org/software.
[music]
>> Welcome to software engineering radio.
I'm Priyanka Ragavan and today we'll be
discussing the topic six store. Our
guest today is Dan Luren, co-founder and
CEO of software supply chain security
company Chain Guard. Dan has been
working on and worrying about containers
for a very long time. We listen to a lot
of his podcasts and I wanted to
previously talk about something that Dan
has mentioned in lot of his podcasts
that I've listened to that he really was
passionate about securing supply chains
right from 2015 as an engineer and a
manager. He was on SE radio discussing
software supply chain attacks in episode
535. And at SE Radio, we've also done
other episodes on software supply chain
securities such as episode 541 on
securing the supply chain and episode 66
on third party supply chain risks. So
great to have you back on the show, Dan,
and welcome.
>> Thanks for having me back.
>> I just wanted to set the stage. It's
2026 and why do software supply chain
attacks matter even today?
>> I'll start by explaining what a software
supply chain attack is and then kind of
give my take on why they matter today
and why they're happening today. A
software supply chain attack is an
attack on the software supply chain.
That's probably pretty basic, but the
software supply chain is all of the
tools and steps and libraries and
components and ingredients that go into
the end software you're using. When you
use any piece of software, a cell phone
app, you swipe your debit card and an
ATM, you check in for a flight, there's
an end application that you're
interacting with there, but that's not
written 100% from scratch every time you
use a piece of software. That software
is made up of tons of reusable
components. That's how teams are able to
ship so much amazing software today.
You're not starting from scratch every
single time. And that software supply
chain is very large today. There's tons
of different programming languages and
libraries and tools and build systems
that go into getting those raw
ingredients, those things at the very
very start into that finished piece of
software that you get to use. It's a
complicated system that goes across
companies, it grows across
organizations, it goes across countries,
especially when you take open source
into account. And so there's a lot of
links to that supply chain. Like any
chain, it's only as strong as the
weakest ones. So an attack is some kind
of an attacker or a nation state, a
criminal, someone exploits some
vulnerabilities somewhere in that supply
chain to get access to the end result.
So instead of just hacking into a system
by coming in through the front door,
they're getting into that system by
coming in through the back door, the
supply chain itself. And once you get
code into that finished product, it's
kind of game over. You know, code
execution. And attackers in recent years
have started to pay more and more
attention to this space. It's not
necessarily easier to do than other ways
of hacking systems, but over the last
10, 15 years, the industry has gotten a
lot better at securing all of the other
ways in. If you log into your bank
today, you have to use two-factor
authentication and things like that that
weren't around six or seven years ago or
were around, but only used by really
security critical organizations. Now,
it's everywhere. Those text messages you
get when you log in to any of your
accounts online, that's all done to make
it harder to steal people's passwords to
break into systems. So because we've
done such a good job keeping attackers
out in all of these other ways, they
pivot to the next easiest way, which is
the supply chain. And at the same time,
open source has grown in ubiquity, grown
in usage. It's made its way into some of
these most sensitive environments. And
so there's a lot more of a surface area
for these attacks to take place on. And
I think when we talk about securing the
software supply chain last year there
was this huge attack towards the end of
the year which was on the npm registry
where it's called shy hallowed and the I
think there were some 500 repositories
which were affected and it was basically
a replicating worm.
>> Yeah.
>> I wanted to ask you about that. Could
you shed some light on that before we
move into sig store?
>> Yeah. So shyude was the name of the
attack. It was the name the attackers
chose. The way to detect it was it
created this public repository called
shy hallude. This was chosen by them but
it was an attack on the software supply
chain in npm in the node.js package
manager. They compromised a couple
packages at the start by doing basic
account takeovers for the maintainers of
those packages and instead of just
attacking those packages it was a
self-replicating worm in the npm
registry. So one of the things it did
was steal credentials. So if you used
one of the affected libraries while you
were publishing other npm packages,
which is very common, it stole
credentials to publish packages to npm
and it inserted that malware into all
the affected packages. And so it spread
very very quickly. I don't remember the
final stats, but I saw there was a crazy
like double-digit percentages of the
internet were basically affected by this
very very quickly because of that
exponential nature. They hacked one and
then spread that way. It was taken down
by npm, but then since the attackers
have done it two or three more times,
there was shyoon part one, part two, and
part three.
>> Yeah,
>> it was a big wakeup call. One, because
of how fast it spread and I think two
because it was one of the first ones
that stole credentials in that way.
These attacks have been happening weekly
for years, but for the most part, the
attackers have kind of settled on
installing crypto miners on people's
laptops or in systems like that as a way
of making money off of the attack.
That's not great, but it's also not the
end of the world. there are a lot worse
things attackers can do like ransomware
or stealing sensitive data or something
like that once they have that code
execution in your environment and so
this is one of the first times the
attackers actually went after more than
just free crypto coins where your
electricity bill goes up a little bit if
this thing gets installed so it's kind
of a big wakeup moment for the industry
>> and let's now come into sig store what
is it can you explain that to our
listeners
>> yeah I'll start with the problem that
shy hallude exploited and then connect
that back to how sig store designed to
help prevent some of these and then we
can kind of talk about the architecture
and how it all works. But when we first
talk about open source, the definition
of open source is actually a legal
definition. It's not anything related to
programming or GitHub or access or
anything like that. There's a group
called the OSI, the open source
initiative, and they maintain a bunch of
definitions about what type of license
software has to be released under to be
considered open source. There's a bunch
of principles in there that licenses
have to follow. And they review licenses
and have a list of ones that they've
reviewed that they will attest meet kind
of this standard, but that applies to
the source code itself. That applies to
the JavaScript files themselves. If
you're talking about Node.js or the py
Python files for Python, unfortunately,
that's not actually how most
organizations consume open source. They
don't get it in that source code form.
They get these packages which have been
transformed from source code into
something that's a lot easier to run. In
the JavaScript and Python cases, they
include things like native builds
depending on what platform you're
running on and things like that. So if
you're looking at the source code for a
package and then you install that
package, they might be two separate
things. There's actually no direct link
from the source code that is up on
GitHub to the open source package that
you have downloaded and installed on
your computer. In fact, most people when
they publish a package, they download
that source code, they compile it on a
laptop, and then they upload it to a
different system. So that's where npm
comes in for the node ecosystem. People
aren't npm installing packages from
GitHub. They're installing from npm. So
two separate systems and there's no real
evidence that the npm package you
installed has any correlation to the
source code for that package back over
on GitHub. And that's the link that a
lot of these attackers have been
exploiting. You might review the source
and say, "This is great. There's no
malware in here. There are no
vulnerabilities. I've checked it all."
But then when you install it, boom,
there's malware in there because
somebody slipped it in at that step.
There's a lot of steps in the supply
chain. And there are a lot of places the
stuff could be inserted, but that one is
the most common. Sig store is designed
to provide a cryptographic link between
any of these steps in the supply chain.
Signatures signed by people, signed by
systems, something like that that says
this npm package actually came from this
piece of source code. It's an
irreversible step. You can't actually go
back and check this kind of thing. But
with signatures, you get kind of this
promise from some person with an
identity in the signature there that
says, "Yes, I am this person. And I took
this software from here and I put it
over here. And systems like SIG store,
it's not the first one to kind of do
signing in this way, cryptographic
signing, but it was one of the first
ones designed to do this at scale for
open source. There have been systems
around before like PGP where people do
key signing parties and stuff like that
to verify identities, but Six Door is
set up in a way where any developer can
get keys whenever they need them.
They're tied to identities like email
addresses or build systems or things
like that. So you can kind of get this
verifiable proof that the source code
hasn't been tampered with along the way.
If you go back to other analogies in
like the food safety industry store is
like that tamperproof seal on the jar of
pasta sauce or something you buy.
>> It doesn't tell you if the ingredients
are good. It doesn't really tell you if
it's expired. If something happened in
the manufacturing and they have to be
recalled, it can't really prevent that,
but it can tell you that the tamperproof
seal hasn't been removed in shipping
that jar to you. And so it's one piece
in a an important ecosystem of trying to
secure and harden all of those links of
the supply chain.
>> Okay. Yeah, that's a great analogy. I
wanted to ask you when you actually sign
this or make it tamperroof and you
talked mainly about open source, but can
this also be used for internal libraries
and containers?
>> Yeah, lots of organizations run this
same technology internally. That's an
important part of securing internal
supply chains. Insider risk is a pretty
important problem inside of large
companies. making sure that individuals
whether they're doing it on purpose or
unintentionally if say their laptop gets
compromised or something don't have
unilateral permissions to change the
running code in production. These things
have to be reviewed by multiple people
and sig store is also used by a lot of
companies internally to do all of that.
If you have a whole bunch of controls
and policies in place saying that things
have to be built on this build system to
make it to production store can be used
in that way too.
>> Would you have like a risk profile to
say for the thing that's signed? I know
you said it's you can't really check
what is inside but is there some kind of
a risk profile maintained?
>> No. So you can kind of build those
systems on top of sig store but at the
end of the day it comes down to trust.
You have to trust someone. If a bunch of
organizations have tested it and
verified that it works correctly they
can publish that on the internet too.
You can kind of build higher level
systems on top of sig store. You could
say I'm only going to run something that
three other people have said is good and
safe and trustworthy. and the ledger
which is a core component of SIG store
is a place where all of those pieces of
evidence can be cryptographically signed
and verified that if Dan said this is
good software and he's fine with it then
I know that Dan actually said that.
>> So one of the things I also was
listening to and reading a couple of
posts when I was researching for 62 was
the popularity or something that what
Sikro wants to achieve is like let's
encrypt where they drove the adoption of
HTTPS. So can you talk a little bit
about that? Let's Encrypt I talked about
before. We've done a good job hardening
other systems and so now attackers are
pivoting to the supply chain. Let's
Encrypt is probably one of the reasons
software supply chain attacks are
happening because they made it really
easy to get certificates that are used
to secure the web. Signed certificates
when you at the top of your browser that
little green lock icon that goes up
showing that it's a secure connection.
It's been around for decades. But to get
one of these certificates in the past
you had to fill out a lot of paperwork.
You had to find a domain registar verify
who your company identity was and then
they would give you this certificate and
a certificate is really just a digital
document a text file that that domain
registar or certificate authority has
signed saying okay chainguard.dev dev.
That's my company's website. That's
actually owned by Chain Guard, a
company. And then when you log on to the
website, you can make sure that you
haven't been man-in-the-middle attacked,
right? Someone in the internet in
between you and that company isn't
tampering with the website anymore. The
bits you see on your screen are exactly
the ones that that company wants you to
be seeing. And if you send data to them,
it's going to that company and no one in
the middle can read it. It's been around
for a very long time, but it was
annoying to set up. So, most people
didn't unless you were a bank or
something like that where people were
typing their passwords and you wanted to
make sure that was encrypted and going
to the right person. Let's Encrypt have
automated all of this. Instead of having
to do this manual process and writing
checks and logging into credit cards and
that kind of thing, you would just set
up an automated system and they would
automatically prove that you controlled
that domain name and that nothing had
been tampered with along the way as a
result of making it free and easy to use
and automatic. Encryption on the
internet went from low double digits to
close to 100%. And now browsers require
it. And if you go to a domain that
doesn't have one of those, they make you
type in like, I am okay accepting this
risk before they'll even show you the
page. That only happens when you get to
that level of ubiquity. And doing that
at internet scale is very hard, right?
We're talking millions of websites, tons
of people, tons of different web
browsers involved. It's an ecosystem
level change that they were able to roll
out by taking something that was hard
and making it free and easy for anyone
to adopt. Code signing and that kind of
thing was in a similar place before Sig
store. It was really hard to get code
signing certificates. No one was really
doing it and nothing in open source was
really signed even if it was and no one
was checking the signatures because they
didn't expect it to be signed and they
didn't know how. So as we designed and
built Sig Store we were heavily inspired
by the let's encrypt system and how they
operate and how they proved that they
haven't been attacked and things like
that at the same time. So make it free,
make it easy and make it automatic for
developers to do that signing. So we can
eventually get to a world where enough
stuff is signed that people can start
requiring it and it looks weird if you
download something that hasn't been
signed. the same way your browser won't
even show you a website that doesn't
have a certificate today.
>> Exactly. So that's the vision to go to
that kind of an adoption.
>> Yeah. I don't know what attackers are
going to go to next when open source
gets to that point, but yeah, that's how
this game is played.
>> Okay. So let's move on to the next part
of the podcast where we want to talk a
little bit about the main components and
what makes six store work. So could you
talk us a little bit about the main
components of the six store? How does
the signing work? Yeah. So, signing and
certificates and all of that kind of
stuff at the end of the day boil down to
identity. Certificates themselves are
just a bunch of random numbers. You
can't really read them. I'm not going to
remember your massive random number if
you told it to me. They're way too long
to remember. But a certificate is a way
of tying that to some kind of identity,
whether it's a person's name, a
pseudonym, a GitHub account, an email
address, the name of a build system
running somewhere. They're a way of kind
of stepping up a level from private keys
which are just random numbers to
identities. And that's the first problem
to solve in open source because identity
management is very hard. Some people I
mean it's Torvalds. Everyone knows who
he is. He's the maintainer of Linux for
any given package on Pippi. You might
not know who the maintainers are or who
their names are. They might not want you
to know all of that. But you need some
kind of root for that identity, some
kind of shared system. When it turns out
that there's already this protocol for
that called open ID connect. when you go
to log into a website and they don't
make you make an account, they have, you
know, login with Google, login with
Apple, those kind of buttons, that's
using that protocol. So, it's a way to
tie someone's identity to an email
address. Basically, at the end of the
day, there are other forms of that
identity for servers and different
naming schemes, but you can think of it
as that login with Google button that
appears on most websites. For most
people, it is their digital identity at
the end of the day, their email address.
And so, when you start with Sort, that's
kind of the root. It's the email
addresses of people that are maintaining
these projects. So everything is kind of
built up from there. There's a system
that does that login with Google Flow.
So you don't need to have certificates
anymore. Every time you want to sign
something, you get this temporary
certificate that's just used for signing
that one piece of code that's tied to an
email address. So you can't really say
which private key signs something at any
given time. That doesn't make sense
because they're just random numbers. But
you can say this email address signed
this thing at this time. At its root,
that's what Sig store is. There's a
whole bunch of components that make that
work and make that secure, but that's
how it's able to be accessible to
developers. They don't have to worry
about all of this key management and
what happens if a key gets leaked or
what happens if I lose it. Oh,
>> great. So, the keys are basically your
email address. That's the main
>> basically. Yeah. And then there's a
bunch of cryptography behind the scenes
to make that work.
>> I was just thinking when I was asking
this question to you, why not GitHub
IDs? Is that because you don't want to
be tied to GitHub? Yeah, they're one of
the possible providers. So I I mentioned
mostly email addresses. GitHub is also
supported. There's a bunch of different
forms of identity that you can use in
here, but at the end of the GitHub
account is usually tied to an email
address, too.
>> Right. Right. Oh, that makes sense. And
also maybe there's somebody using some
other source control. So yeah, by having
the
>> enterprises configure this internally,
they can set it up with their active
directory or their octa or whatever
identity provider use inside of their
companies. So the protocol is open ID
connect but then behind the scenes it
could be any kind of identity provider
>> protocol. Yeah.
>> And I guess the artifacts that are used
that are signed are they just the
containers uh binaries?
>> It can be anything. Yeah. There's a
bunch of things that are supported as
first class in SIG store. But at the end
of the day you're just signing a digest.
You're not really signing the container.
You're signing the digest of the
container. You're signing the digest of
the Python package. You're signing the
digest of the Java package. something
that there's a bunch of tooling to make
it easy to work with containers or
Python packages or node packages, but
you can sign a note, you can sign a
tweet, you can sign an email. Yeah.
>> And I think the next thing is of course
you sign it. And the big thing is also
to verify it.
>> Yeah, that's the hard part. Anyone can
sign something, but it only works if
people are actually checking those
signatures. So yeah, when you go to
check one of these signatures, you know,
cryptography again just works with
random numbers basically. But because
it's the way Salix is designed, if you
want to check a signature, you can check
which email address assigned it. And
that's kind of the flow. You sign it
with your email address. You can check
the signatures and it'll tell you which
email addresses have signed something.
So that's how you know if again Sig
store can't tell you if something is
good. You have to know if you trust that
email address, but it can tell you that
that email address sign something. And
you have to decide if that's meaningful
to you and if you trust that.
>> What about the audit logs, which they
call transparency logs? I saw a lot
about that. Yeah, that's kind of how all
of this works under the covers. If
you're someone signing things with your
email address, you're trusting this
other system. You're trusting Sig Store
at the end of the day to not lie or to
not be compromised or to not publish
something that wasn't really your email
address. Sig store were to get
compromised. If your email address were
to get compromised, any of these things,
then people could be publishing
signatures on your behalf. That's bad
because if people trust you and all of a
sudden those signatures end up out
there, then they're not going to trust
you anymore. And there's this other
cryptographic primitive. Again, it's
used by Let's Encrypt and it's used by,
you know, all HTTPS certificates in the
world, but they're called transparency
logs. It's this appendon ledger that you
can prove hasn't been tampered with over
time and that everyone is kind of seeing
that same ledger. So, it's kind of trust
through openness. At any given time, I
can go check that SIG store ledger for
everything that I have assigned as a
person and I know that the signatures
won't validate unless they're in that
transparency log. Um, so it's kind of a
couple steps, but it's did this email
address sign it and is it in that log?
Again, that's dependent on people
checking that log to make sure that
things aren't showing up in there that
shouldn't be. But that's kind of the
only way all of these moving parts fit
together in a place where developers
don't really have to trust SIG store.
They have to trust that everything will
be in the open. And if something does
end up in there, you can trace it back
to figure out what happened. Was it that
someone compromised my email address?
Was it that the infrastructure got
compromised? And you have these
timestamps and you can see exactly what
happened when. You don't have to
invalidate everything. You can say, "Oh,
out of these, you know, 100 signatures,
99 of them were valid and actually me,
but this one isn't." And you can
everyone can then be notified that that
piece had been tampered with. Similar in
some ways to blockchain, but a different
use case for it. But yeah, every time
you go to google.com, you get a
certificate for Google. And Google is
trusting a certificate authority to not
lie, not be compromised, and not issue
certificates to attackers. The way
they're able to trust that other party
is through transparency logs there too.
There are people at Google monitoring
that log to make sure no certificates
end up in there. They don't belong to
them. This is really important at
internet scale because again internet
scale is global and different countries
control different certificate
authorities and things like that and
there's no real universal law that
applies here. This operating in this
world where you know nation states are
funding large cyber attacks. It's hard
to really trust any of these components
in their mobile world. So trust through
transparency is what what this whole
ecosystem is built on.
>> So that means I as a maintainer of an
open-source package as soon as I sign
something I should go and check the
transparency log. I mean that happens
automatically I guess part of the
infrastructure but then someone who's
picking up a package that I have built
would go and check the transparency log.
I mean how does that work for uh
>> so that's all automatic and built in.
When you go to check that signature you
say did was this signed by Dan? it goes
to make sure that signature is in the
transparency log. There's systems people
have set up to send you an email every
time a signature for your email ends up
in that transparency log and things like
that. So, yeah, it's kind of on you to
be checking these systems and
everything, but it makes it easy to
spot. Yeah, every time my signature
appears in there, I get an email address
or I get an email to my email address.
And if I didn't publish anything that
day, that's a big red flag.
>> Looking for a way to stand out in a
competitive job market? Whether you're
trying to land your first contributor
role or prove you can deliver, take the
next step in your career with the new
software professional certification from
the ITE computer society.
Sign up today at
computer.org/certification.
So I think the other thing I wanted to
ask you is I saw a little bit about the
key tools which is like cosign and then
fullo which is like the certificate
manager and I think recor which is for
the audit logs. Now these are the
infrastructure which is provided from
what I see just you can just use these
kind of command line tools right?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. So most people in the open source
world when they interact with it will
just use one of the tools like cosign
cosign is for signing containers
container signing there's other versions
for python other versions for node and
that interacts with those systems full
co is the piece that does that identity
check so like a little when you go when
you run cosign sign your browser pops up
and you click yes and sign in with
Google that's full co then there's the
that ledger we talked about that
transparency log that's recor so when
fullco issues those certificates when
you do those signatures all of that ends
up in the transparency log. So that's
kind of all wrapped up into one of those
interfaces like cosine or the Python
version or the Node.js version or
whatever it is depending on what you're
signing. Six store is a pretty
interesting project because it's it's an
open source project but those two
components Fio and Recor they're
actually operated as a shared
infrastructure. So the open SSF the open
source security foundation it's part of
the Linux Foundation runs a it's called
the public good instance. It's run
there's a team of people that carry
pagers from you know volunteers from
different companies. A few folks from my
company, Chain Guard, are on that
rotation and they keep the system
running. There's databases involved,
there's servers, things have to be
upgraded, but those are run for the
benefit of everyone in in open source
that are signing things and verifying
things. If you're a company running this
stuff internally, you could publish
things in there, but you might not want
everyone to know how many deployments
you did that week or something like
that. Some people view that as sensitive
information. So, companies can run their
own instances of that and they'll have,
you know, a team running those. They
publish their internal signatures and
keys and logs too.
>> If I was to integrate this with a CI/CD
pipeline, how does it work? Are there
like tools for that or
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, we talked about email
addresses being the main form of
identity. It's not the only one. An open
ID connect supports a bunch of other
ones. Um, another common one is called
workload identity. If you're doing this
from a CI/CD system, it doesn't have an
email address. What's the email address
of, you know, your Jenkins server or
something like that? There are other
ways to do identity at that level. So
you can if you're on a cloud provider,
they have a lot of this stuff baked in.
So you can say only this CI/CD system
running in Amazon in this zone on this
instance is trusted and you can get a
different form of identity tied to, you
know, that exact virtual machine or that
exact Kubernetes pod or something like
that. Wherever these things are running,
it's still just a string. It kind of
looks like an email address, but it's
not an email address. And so those
systems can get certificates tied to the
workload in whatever way you want to
define workload. All of the cloud
providers support, you know, different
ways of doing that. GitHub actions has
it baked in. So you can say, you know,
this GitHub action running from this
repository on this branch is allowed to
publish into this registry or into this
cluster. It's just a different, you
know, way of formatting that piece of
identity.
>> While you were answering this, my mind
also went into like AI agents,
autonomous agents. So it's also would be
the same type of workload identities,
right? or
>> yeah there's been a lot of work in that
space both around you know signing
models themselves making sure that the
model you get say from hugging face or
something like that is the real model
that's kind of similar to a container
right it's just you know a bunch of
bites at the end of the day as well as
yeah if you want to say this AI agent
running here is allowed to push commits
to this repository that's a similar
identity system
>> probably it also has a specific identity
tied to not an email address but a
workload identity okay
>> exactly
>> let's Let's go a little bit about the
real world impact. I wanted to ask you
how give me some examples of projects
using sig
>> tons the kubernetes project signs all of
their release artifacts with sig store.
Python itself like if you go download a
build of Python that's signed with SIG
store and then it's also baked into
Pippi now it's opt in you're not
required to use it but there's a whole
flow called trusted publishing inside of
Pippi and npm where you can turn it on
and say yeah only this GitHub action is
allowed to publish you know these wheel
files to Pippi or these npm packages to
npm and it's kind of starting to build
up that you know green lock icon at the
top of your browser being used all over
open source It's Maven Central supports
it for publishing Java artifacts now
too. So it's been a fast growth over the
last couple of years.
>> And when you talk about npm, I was just
thinking cuz I use it a lot and my day
job right now. So if I I usually do this
npm install and then get the packages,
right? So can I also give some
instructions to say that I should only
install packages that are signed in six
store?
>> I forget how they baked it into the
client at verification but yeah that
would be the flow something like that.
you allow signed packages, check
signatures,
the policy that my organization has
defined around who's allowed to, you
know, which type of packages we trust.
>> Okay. So, you can actually set up
something in your config and then do a
>> Yeah, I don't use npm too much, but I'm
pretty sure there's something
>> we shall like probably look it up and
add a show notes to the same. I also
wanted to ask you in terms of when
you're using sig store, how much of a
maintenance impact is it on your
project? Because it's one more thing to
do, right? Is it really easy? I mean,
hearing what you're saying, it sounds
easy, but what are the overheads?
>> Yeah, signing stuff with it is really
easy. It's just running an extra command
inside of every build. The hard part is,
yeah, the the second half, making sure
people are verifying them. That's the
second piece.
>> And then when you sign an artifact, can
you prevent supply chain attacks?
>> Yeah, if people are checking them. Yeah,
signing does nothing by itself. But
yeah, if the maintainers of the first
set of packages that were, you know, hit
with shy hallude had been signing
things, the signatures wouldn't
invalidated after someone else directly
bypassed that and uploaded directly
10pm.
>> Are you taking action as a maintainer to
allow your consumers to protect
themselves? It's kind of the way I would
explain it. They still have to take that
step to protect themselves, but you've
now made it possible for them. So if you
see some kind of wrong entry on a
package that you're maintaining then you
kind of notify all the people who are
using your package.
>> Yeah. You can take it down. You have to
publish something on hacker news you
know saying hey this has been
compromised.
>> Yeah. Stop using it.
>> Okay. Okay. It seems like things like
shy would be less of a problem if you
use things like this. Yeah.
>> If everything was using it. Yeah. We
talked a little bit briefly about you
know signing models that I I saw that
even Google is basically signing all
their ML models with SIG store. Can you
talk a little bit about what have you
heard?
>> Yeah, it's similar to signing anything a
little bit different. The model is much
larger. There's different protocols and
things for where the signatures get
placed. But yeah, when you're a company
distributing stuff like that and people
are rehosting on lots of different
websites, if one of those were to get
compromised, that would look bad for you
because people uh you know thought it
was the Google model or something like
that. So it's a way of kind of securing
all of those links. There's a working
group again in the open SSF around how
to sign models and how to validate that
and baking that into all of the tooling
as well to make it easy. It's all based
on that those core six store primitives.
>> One of the things that you've been
saying is it all depends very much on
how you verify the signed packages. And
I wanted to ask you in this context
because we've also had many attacks in
software supply chain where you know
there's this typo squatting you you
might just pick up something which is
similar to the name. Yeah. Like one of
those popular pi packages or whatever.
Now the thing is what I wanted to ask
you is these kind of attacks do they
come down with a sig store or not really
right. Yeah, and you know, I kind of
glanced over this and caught myself
right after, but yeah, typo squatting is
real. And so I mentioned before like
there is a flow in SIG store to say who
signed to this package and it will print
out the email addresses. That's actually
not secure because if you just read
those email addresses, there's all these
unic code attacks where like you know it
might be a different version of the at
symbol or something in the middle or
something like that. So better way to do
it is to say here is the exact you type
in the email address and say only allow
it if that exact one signed it. because
of things like typo squatting. I could
go make an email address today that
looks just like yours but with like a
unic code character in the middle that
looks the same but isn't actually the
same at the end of the day and if you're
relying on just looking at the words. So
people make mistakes and it's really
hard to notice a lot of these. So that
same kind of thing happens in Sig Store
2 and it's they've changed the default
to make it hard to do that by accident.
You have to type in the email address
and it'll tell you whether or not that
email address signed it instead of just
printing out the email address and
letting you do visual inspection. This
stuff is really subtle. But yeah, typo
spotting attacks happen all the time and
it again it you want to know the
identities of the people not necessarily
the names of the package at the end of
the day.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> It doesn't solve it by itself but again
it gives you you know ways to solve it.
>> I wanted to ask you if there's sort of
one practical step towards you know
maintaining supply chain integrity. What
can a small team do
>> inside of a company? I think you know
the biggest thing is stop. If you're
doing this today don't do it. Stop doing
it. But don't ever publish anything from
people's laptops, right? Move to a build
system and require everything that goes
to prod to come from that build system.
You then have to secure that build
system and make sure it's not
compromised. But it's a much lower
attack surface than everyone's laptops.
And it forces you to adopt a lot of this
hygiene and practices to make sure that
things are flowing through one point
before they get into production.
>> So definitely not from your laptop and
go to a build system and do it from
there. And the other thing I wanted to
ask you is also is there like a sample
first project or demo for beginners that
they can try out?
>> There's a bunch of getting started
guides on sig store but yeah the easiest
to just download the cosign tool. If
you're doing anything with containers
just download cosign it's really easy to
use. Just do cosine sign and the name of
the container and it kind of guides you
through the rest.
>> Okay.
>> There's good flows if you're using
GitHub actions. There's flows if you're
using GitLab. There's flows if you're
using you know tons of basic CI/C
systems out there.
>> Okay. So I now have to ask you a little
bit about what Chain Guard does. Can you
tell us a little bit further?
>> Chain Guard is a software supply chain
security company at the end of the day
and we're trying to build a safe source
for open source software. So because
open source is such a massive and
distributed problem and even though
these tools are out there, you can't
just go expect tens of millions of
developers to adopt them overnight.
That's kind of what we do here at
Changard. We take all of the open source
that our customers need and rebuild it
from source directly. We do all this
stuff like using sig store and hardened
build systems to make the salsa
standards along the way produce all
those signatures into the final
artifacts. We have our containers
product which is a set of you know over
2,000 container images where every piece
of software in there is built from
source by us in our build systems.
Everything is signed from start to
finish and then people get access to
this catalog of all of these safe
container images. And then we also
automate the other half of the supply
chain security problem. Today we've kind
of focused on the malware and tampering
piece around sig store but there's also
you know the ingredient problem too we
talked about there's tons of instances
log 4j is probably you know the most
well-known one nothing malicious just a
vulnerability that makes its way in all
code has bugs some of those bugs cause
security issues we automate the patching
life cycle of all those vulnerabilities
that come out so everything is up to
date all patches are applied and you get
stuff that hasn't been tampered with and
stuff that has all the vulnerabilities
patched
>> okay so it's done automatically for I
mean know you take the newer version of
what's available on
>> chain cut.
>> Tons and tons of automation to keep
everything up to date whenever known
vulnerabilities are found.
>> Okay, that's really good because
otherwise I'm spending most of our time
doing pseudo app get on everything. So
that's kind of taken care of. I wanted
to ask you what's different between say
like you have these CIS benchmarks which
are done for virtual machine images
right like so is that sim something
similar that happens with the I mean
like is this this is a container image
but yeah maybe is that what you're
attempting
>> yeah we also do that so we give you
these artifacts and then there's tons of
different ways to run these things I
know if you run if you get a super
secure container image or a VM that has
been secured and getting you everything
but it runs as root and has all of these
extra components in it that don't need
to be there. You got a super secure
supply chain give you something that is
now insecure when you put it into
production. And that's what a lot of
these benchmarks are. They're CIS
benchmarks. The US government has
another program called Stig. And it's
kind of a checklist of like if you're
going to run this particular database,
here's how to do it securely. You know,
don't have basic password access. Make
sure you change the default passwords,
that kind of thing. So, it's a checklist
for making sure you've configured the
software to run in a secure manner at
the end, too. And we also do that.
>> And I think I have to also ask you
another question. And sometimes you have
the very slim images which are produced
right and that also becomes sometimes
it's a bit too slim and then you end up
sort of you can't really do anything
sometimes with some of the very slim
images you can't really run a lot of
things and then you have to install
things. So, how does that problem happen
for your customers? Because I'm sure you
are also building slim images, but then
everybody has a different want, right?
So, how what happens then?
>> It's a series of trade-offs. Yeah. Some
people depending on how sensitive of an
environment you're running in, how
regulated your industry happens to be.
You might need them to be fully
hardened, fully locked down, no extra
attack surface, that kind of thing in
these images. And that's our default.
you know, we believe in, you know,
secure by default instead of insecure by
default and then making everyone go
secure things, but it is a spectrum. Not
everyone needs that. If there's no shell
in your container image that's running
in production and something's going
wrong, it's very hard to debug that. It
changes the equation on a lot of things.
Um, but depending on how secure you need
to be or what your regulations say, you
might need that in place. But we have a
whole spectrum, you know, for all the
stuff we ship, you know, that's our
default, but we have, you know, full
versions of all of the container images
that have the shell, the package
manager, all that kind of stuff that you
might be used to and familiar with. So
you can start there and work your way
down.
>> Okay. So different flavors based on what
you're developing. Okay.
>> Different levels of hardening kind of.
Yeah.
>> The last segment I want to talk a little
bit about AI. you know we have so many
coding assistants and everybody's
producing so much of code and then also
sometimes the coding assistants are also
telling you you know install this
package and and in certain programming
languages for example if I'm not
familiar with the programming language
I'll just use the coding assistants help
and then pick up a package can that be
something that's that's also vulnerable
is something that six door also trying
to get in there to see if the coding
assistants are also like looking up I
don't know it's just
>> yeah there's a bunch of different
problems I think here. But overall, I
think we're heading toward a good
future, right? You know, coding
assistance, all of these tools. Yeah,
>> you know, right now more people can
write software. There's going to be a
lot more software written from the
pessimist side. You know, again, I said
all software has bugs. Some of those
bugs cause security issues. If there's a
ton more software out there, they're
going to be a ton more security issues.
These same systems that produce code can
also check for security issues. They can
also fix security issues. Agents never
get tired, right? They never need a
break like people do. And we're going to
get to a world where there's a lot more
a lot better software as a result here.
But it's going to require people to not
just use the agents to write code and
ship that to production tomorrow, right?
We're going to have to figure out what
it means to be secure. How to automate
that into the process and then let the
agents do that too. Yeah, I think things
are going to move faster. We're going to
get a lot more software built. It's
going to be cheaper. It's going to be
better for everyone. But yeah, in the
short term, there's a lot coming and
slop published and all of that stuff.
But I think over time it's it's just
going to improve things for everyone.
>> Yeah. So probably we'll have an agent
for picking out the right images from
chain guard or an agent for making sure
things are verified.
>> We have a lot of this going on
internally.
>> Okay. So like a different agent for each
of these activities. I think yeah that
makes sense. So I think yeah people are
doing that. So apart from the coding
part you also have the different agents
to take care of the security angle and
the sanity angle. Yeah, that makes sense
and I think that kind of also ties in
with what you spoke about which is also
ensuring that the agents have a good
machine identity which is again part of
what we discussed before. I think that's
about it. I think that's all I've had
questions for you. And before I let you
go, I need to ask you where can people
reach you on the internet if they wanted
to connect?
>> LinkedIn's probably the best place. My
name is Dan Lawrence. That's L O R E N
C. Find me there, but I post all the
time. I'll add that to the show notes
and thank you for coming on Software
Engineering Radio. This has been a great
conversation.
>> Yeah, thanks for having me. [music]
>> Thanks for listening to SE Radio, an
educational program brought to you by
Ile E Software Magazine. For more about
the podcast, including other episodes,
visit our website at se-radio.net.
[music] To provide feedback, you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn, Facebook,
Twitter, or through our Slack channel at
seradio. slack.com. [music]
You can also email us at
teamse-radio.net.
This and all other episodes of SE Radio
is licensed under Creative Common
[music] License 2.5. Thanks for
listening.